you're watching nbc 4 the tri-state news
channel and now felicia taylor rob
morrison and aubry puente this is
newschannel 4 weekend today in new york
more than 11 000 youngsters have been
making inroads on the path to a
successful career thanks to a special
program you might describe it as a
corporate internship with a twist linda
bacaro explains in this week's viciones
this is a public affairs presentation of
nbc4
vizionis
just this week becky perez was promoted
to a top post at prudential insurance in
newark heading up the department that
creates recruitment strategies and she
says it's due to a unique internship
program she participated in several
years ago called inroads they
talked to me about corporate culture and
presentation skills communication skills
and what it really takes to succeed in
corporate america if that's what i
wanted to do and i and i did and i'm
completely pleased with uh with the
results so far we have partners in
accounting firms we have vice presidents
we have presidents of their own firms we
have presidents of divisions of major
corporations so the success is really
starting to take hold in its 30 years
inroads has put 11 000 underserved youth
on the road to success nilo barredo is a
senior at rutgers university and for
four years now has interned with lucent
technology at a meeting of prospective
corporate sponsors
talked up the advantages of inroads
interns
if they're given the correct work if
they're put in touch with the right
people
they'll come on full time and
as i said be your future if you're
looking to have
your company reflect society inroads is
a great program because it gives you
that diverse background that every
company needs to make better decisions
inroads has a the who's who of corporate
america and here in northern new jersey
companies like prudential chubb
insurance
att lucent technologies my firm
pricewaterhousecoopers
companies pay a sponsorship fee to win
rhodes and students usually work summers
only
they need to maintain a great gpa to be
accepted into inroads
they need to show some dynamics
it is extremely competitive to become a
part of this organization and to be
hired on as an intern but it is a very
big investment and you need to make a
decision whether you want to invest your
summers working full-time inroads
conducts trainings throughout the summer
on saturdays so it really is a six day
work week six years after graduating
from the in rhodes program and looking
to be hired by prudential becky perez
now finds herself in the unique position
of doing the hiring for prudential and
she says she often turns to inroads
graduates
the combination of internship and
leadership development training has
resulted in 70 percent of inroads
graduates being offered permanent
positions perez says those students are
making their mark on corporate america
and if you take full advantage of all
the resources that inroads has for you
there's no doubt you're going to succeed
and that's viciones for this week i'm
linda baccaro
this is a public affairs presentation of
nbc 4
vizionis